Bridget Shannon

(904) 568-8032 | bridgetrshannon@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin.com/in/bridget-shannon</u> | <u>Github.com/bridgetrshannon</u> | <u>Bridgetrshannon.github.io</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer leveraging a background in education to build a more inviting and accessible user experience on the web. Recently earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Central Florida honing skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. With previous experience as an educator, excited to bring problem solving skills and a creative mindset to developing web applications. My most recent project was a volunteer search application, Assist. On a team with another developer, we created an application that allows users to search for, save, and create volunteer opportunities. This app uses React.js, JavaScript, MongoDB, MDBootstrap, and Charity Navigator API. I'm looking forward to using my skills as part of a socially-conscious, quality-driven team to build better web experiences for all users.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ajax, Axios, APIs, Node.js, MySQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, UiKit, Handelbars.js, MDBootstrap, React Bootstrap, and React.js

PROJECTS & APPLICATIONS

Assist | assist-application.herokuapp.com | github.com/bridgetrshannon/Assist

Assist connects users with volunteer and community engagement opportunities.

- Role: Using MDBootstrap and CSS, styled landing page, user signin and login pages, search results, user profile, create form, and about us page. Used Axios to make requests to Charity Navigator API. JSON Web Token authentication for login, signout, and search features.
- Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JWT, MongoDB, Express, Redux, React, Node.js, MDBootstrap, and Charity Navigator API

Audiophyle | <u>audiophyle-music-platform.herokuapp.com/</u> | <u>github.com/bridgetrshannon/Audiophyle</u> Audiophyle allows users to search for and save their favorite musical artists.

- **Role:** Created wireframes, used CSS and Bootstrap for front-end design of home page, artist search results, and user profile. Assisted my team with API routes and requests.
- Utilized: HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, and TheAudioDB API

Peckish | bridgetrshannon.github.io/Peckish/ | github.com/bridgetrshannon/Peckish

Peckish helps users search for and discover new and exciting food and drink recipes without having to purchase a cookbook.

- Role: Developed all elements for the Social media and Food Inspiration section using UiKit and CSS. Assisted my team with the debugging of our code and API requests.
- Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, TheMealDB and TheCocktailDB APIs, UiKit Framework

The Burger Place | the-burger-place-1.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/bridgetrshannon/Burgers |

The Burger Place allows users to log their choice of burger, change it's devoured status, or delete it.

- Role: Developed all elements; Used Node and MySQL to query and route the data in the application while Handlebars generated the HTML. Used CSS for transparent containers and hover effects with buttons.
- Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, MySQL, Node.js, Express, Handlebars and an ORM

Fitness Tracker | fitness-tracker-5678.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/bridgetrshannon/Fitness_Tracker Fitness Tracker allows users to create and track daily workouts. Users can track the name, type, weight, sets, reps, and duration of exercise.

- **Role:** Developed all elements; used Mongoose for database Schema of exercises, fetch for API to add, delete, and update exercises.
- Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mongoose, and Express

EXPERIENCE

Safety Harbor Middle School; Pinellas County, Florida *Chorus Teacher*, January 2018 – November 2020

- Created and implemented daily lesson plans for Beginning Girls Chorus, Intermediate Girls Chorus, Advanced Ladies Chorus, Boys Chorus, Musical Theatre, and Music Technology
- Managed department financials from fundraiser, concerts, and donations
- Accurately maintained records, including student data, purchase orders, and event organizing
- Attended weekly staff meetings with administrators to analyze test score data and work with content area teams to better improve classroom practices
- Consistently received Excellent and Superior ensemble ratings at District and State competitions

Florida State University, Summer Music Camps; Tallahassee, Florida Assistant Director Night Staff, Instructor, Summers 2016 – 2019

- Supervised a team of 28 night counseling staff
- In coordination with Human Resources, used the website WhenlWork.com to create schedules for my team to ensure full supervision of campers
- Oversaw group mediations between campers
- Conducted bi-weekly meetings with staff and university administrators to analyze the previous week's logistics and identify areas for improvement
- Coordinated recruitment events with university Admissions staff
- Developed lesson plans for and instructed Vocal Diction, Music Appreciation, Musicianship, and Chorus electives

Palm Harbor University High School; Pinellas County, Florida

Florida State University College of Music Internship, Guest Teacher August 2017 – December 2017

- Created and implemented daily lesson plans for Chorus, Musical Theatre, and International Baccalaureate Music
- Attended weekly staff meetings with content area teams to better improve classroom practices
- Accurately maintained records, including student data and purchase orders

Florida State University, University Housing; Tallahassee, Florida **Resident Assistant,** August 2014 – May 2017

- Developed and facilitated programming initiatives for the 6,500 college students living on campus each year.
 Programing topics included: Scholarship, Personal Wellness, Engagement, Appreciation of Difference, and Responsible Citizenship
- Completed 240 hours of Crisis Management training. Topics covered included, but were not limited to, mental health, substance abuse, and intimate partner violence.
- Part of a team that oversaw the safety and wellbeing of 500 residents
- Conducted individual meetings with 57 residents focusing on development, involvement, and identity development

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate; University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida | 2020 A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

Bachelor of Music Education in Choral Music Education; Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida Received Specialization in Special Music Education